[music]
All right, what's up, folks? It's time
for the last section of our complete set
review for Reality Fracture.
Going over every card in the set for
Constructed and for Limited, giving out
the awards you know and love and uh just
having a generally good time. This set
looks really, really good. Uh my early
front runner for best set of the year.
Uh of course, you know, I play the
cards. I I have actually but you know
whatever card look that looks great and
uh yeah regard card limited white blue
black red green and multiolor are all
done you miss them go watch them on
YouTube of course and please take a half
second support the content like comment
subscribe a lot of work goes to set
reviews uh not from K of course but for
myself Nicole and Ryan so support the uh
content and let's get right into
colorless starting out with afterthought
century to uh to get flying whenever it
attacks, exile. It's one card card from
the graveyard. Kind of your typical
limited filler. Not the worst card of
all time. Uh, you know, you see a
callous card, you got to kind of figure
out exactly where you want it in
archetype wise. This card seems at its
best in red white as kind of like an
aggro two drop that can wear counters
pretty well. But, you know, there's a
little bit of graveyard things happening
in this set. Uh, most notably with the
blue white, I'm sorry, the blue black
archetype. Could be a cyborg card
against that. But, you know, it's fine.
I think it's an okay card. Try not to
play it, but if there's a time and a
place for it, there's time and a place
for it.
A card I think you do want to play is
Keeper of the Quiet Hour. Three meta for
a 3-2 ETB empower Jace 2. So, of course,
that means the Jace token. Uh, if you
don't have one, you'll get one. If you
have one, you'll add to it. Similar
similar to a mass. And, uh, minus minus
surveill one minus draw a card. So, this
is twothirds of the way to drawing a
card uh or surveilling a few times. This
card's pretty nice. Uh this was close to
to winning my uh my best my bomb in
common uh for colorless because this
card kind of reads like 32 ETB surveil
one gain two life, right? Where they
choose to attack the planaineswalker so
you don't get to surveil again. That
means you gain two life. and three meta
for a surveile one gain two is kind of
fine, you know. Is it great? No. Is it a
high pick? No. Is it a super serviceable
card in any any deck? Yeah, it's kind of
fine, you know. So, I like this card a
lot. Um, you know, I think this is a
filler card that you're not embarrassed
to play. Um, to the point where it's
like almost pretty solid. And the more
empower Jace you have, you know, a 3-2
EDB draw card is very good. Uh, so it's
not that far off that as long as you're
doing other Empower Jace stuff. So, I
think this card is quietly
a very very solid common uh and not just
a filler card. Not that you take it
highly, but I wouldn't be sad to play
this card in my deck. Constructed
obviously not there J token. Living
library two mana for a 04 six mana sack
this to choose a creature or PL opponent
controls and they shuffle it into their
library.
This is obviously pretty filler if
you're desperate for removal or trying
to stay alive in the late game. I mean,
it can block. okay and kill stuff, but
pretty bad card. I would try to not play
this card in my draft deck if possible.
Medics Kite Sail, two mana for a
equipment pluso NF's flying attack to
gain one life equipped two. Uh this is
the kind of card that's going to be
quite good in the green white vigor
bloom deck. Uh where you're triggering
life gain every single turn. You're
gaining a life and dealing extra damage.
Uh just like fine in aggro decks. Like
if you're playing, you know, singer coil
aggro or red white aggro, just need a
way to push through, you could do worse
than this card. It's kind of fine.
Honestly, I think the kite sail effect,
you know, the plus flying is is not too
shabby. But I think specifically you
want this in your life game deck where
it's actually like a pretty good card.
Murmuring volume. Well, the last common
of the list, so it's going to be our
bombing common. M volume is a manalith
that can spend two mana to tap and
rummage which is pretty good. Honestly,
the biggest fear of the mana rock is
that you are going to flood and there's
a lot of good gold cards in a set, a lot
of good fixing. I can imagine this set
uh having some pretty good uh kind of
suit things going on and a card like
this is a great way to do that. Uh and
again the the the
uh what's it called? The looting is
great to have in the mid to late game
which is awesome. Potioners Trove was a
big surv surprise in uh Stricks Haven
where it was a great common. Anyone know
if this card is better or worse than
Trove? Uh if the format is slower, it's
better. If the one is faster, it's
worse. Even so, seems like a good card.
Uh that's your bomb common unless I
guess it's solar. There's only five
common. There you go. Uh murmuring
volume bomb common for colorless onto
archive arbiter and uncommon. Four for
flyer for six. When it enters, choose
one. So target non-creature online
permanent or gain four life. I mean this
is another serviceable card. It's not
great but if you need a six drop this
can do it for you. This is pretty below
rate these days despite looking like
this would have been a great limited
card you know 10 years ago but you know
it's just okay.
Eye of Jace will matter for an artifact.
You have your upkeep surveill one. Then
if there are seven more cards in your
graveyard sack this deal to an opponent
and gain two life.
pretty weird card. Uh where the payoff
is just two damage and gain two life. So
that isn't really much of a payoff. It's
almost like the uh the payoff is
surveilling one every turn, which is not
particularly amazing. It can fill your
graveyard, I suppose, for uh your the
blue black like threshold stuff. That
seems pretty bad. So think this card's
kind of awful. Uh I could be wrong, but
it looks pretty pretty bad.
Traxxo Scourge Eternal from a 54 doesn't
tap during your untap step. Cast
artifact. Untap. This is a reprint. Um
artifact or creature. You're beaten
down. This card seems fine, you know. Uh
know that it is cast. So putting in a
Heartwood token will not untap this. So
it's a kind of a big deal. Uh but yeah,
I mean I think this card is uh a
serviceable limited card. Not
particularly great. [clears throat]
Cody Ravenous Codeex. Cody returns. I I
do do love Cody. The metaphor a 14 of
you cast a prepared spell, copy the
spell and choose new targets, which is
honestly kind of fine. There's a lot of
prepared spells in limited woolberg and
repair your stuff. I that's just
nothing. That's just like flavor text.
Uh constructive card is not playable,
but I think in limited um this card's
kind of fine. If I have like five or six
prepared creatures in my deck, I don't
think I'm gonna happy playing this card.
The one four for three is is fine
enough. You got a spell or two. It's
pretty good, you know. So, it's not
good, but it's looks like a like a junk
rare, but I think it has it definitely
has a place in limited uh for sure.
K Argent defender.
Look, it's not the most exciting best in
show. Uh this is going to be an
impactful card across all formats. It's
metaphor a 13 artifacts of creatures. Uh
torper Orb. uh don't cause abilities
trigger on entering. That's a very
powerful effect. Um you know like we've
seen this effect in actual torper orb.
We've seen this in doorkeeper thr.
That's often a cyborg card you see in
various formats. This is a clawist
version. Uh so you could just play it in
any deck. It's a car and wishboard
target which is kind of meta of course.
Um you know
get himself.
>> Um but yeah it's a hay pair. It's going
to be relevant in many formats. Uh it's
not very exciting, but I think it is it
is the best card in the combo section
for constructive play. So, um there it
is. Best in the show. Don't play it.
Limited.
The Echoverse Fulcrum to metaphor a
legendary artifact. EDB draw discard tap
five and exile it to destroy creatures
but only at sorcery speed. Kind of cute
in that it's a carnival wrath effect. It
does cost seven, which is the requisite
amount for Tron. Uh, you know, oblivious
zone cost eight back in the day, which
is a little awkward. Uh, but
I don't know. I don't think it's that
good. Like TR is better things to do uh
in uh in modern these days. And then if
you're not toning, like that's just an
obscene amount of mana for a wrath. Draw
and discard is not very exciting on two
mana. Just an expensive clunky card. And
then limit you're going to play it.
They're going to like play around it
obviously. So I think this card is just
pretty mid.
Oh boy. Mama.
>> Good luck,
>> mama.
>> Gigantism.
>> I got bandage for mama though.
>> It's a trap. It's
>> a trap, folks. Emer the extingent doom.
10 out of four. Emer
1212. Flying treble. When you cast a
spell, untap all lands you control. Has
ward sack the permanence. That is the
ability where you can bestow it on a
land. Basically, uh, three mana to exile
it and give a land tap for two
colorless. And you can cast it from
exile.
That's not very good. Uh,
[cheering] three mana to add an extra
mana is not very good at all. It's like
a bad manalith. And you know, if they
were to stone rain that land, that would
be a huge loss for you as well. And then
just casting Emer 10 mana just like
isn't that good. Um, untap all your
lands. Sure, it's a 12 cell flying
trample. It has some level of
protection. uh with the war to sack
three, but like by the time they cast
they can just sack three or whatever,
who cares, you know? So, I don't see a
place to discard basically anywhere. Um
it just I [snorts] don't know, you know,
and then limited like I guess it costs
like nine in limited kind of, but it's
not that good either. Maybe a cool card
to play in red green in your constari
mana ramp deck. always always heart
bloom things or whatever. But uh yeah, a
lot of fancy words for uh the big bad in
magic and not a lot of exciting stuff.
Emer's third card is kind of a stinker.
Sorry mama
lands. We have room of refuge and
someone's getting sued. Uh common
manifixer land energ
manifixer. Uh things are soupy. You get
the idea. But yeah,
dedicated commons. These are the common
dual lands in this set. Uh where we've
got 10 lands, not just the the schools,
all 10 lands, and they enter untapped if
you control a plains walker. Now,
normally that would sound like a crazy
thing to have in a common land, but of
course, we have these chase tokens
literally everywhere in every set uh in
every color. And these are pretty good.
It's not hard to have a Jason play. This
adds a lot of value to your Jases and
honestly makes it really interesting
playing against Jace because you I think
in limited deciding whether or not
you're going to attack the Jace when
it's on one or two is going to be a
really fun like game choice to make and
then possibly oops possibly turning off
your opponent's untapped land is another
way to kind of get some value too. So I
think these are really cool. Um, I think
this is a very unique way to do a common
dual land cycle. Uh, and a very fun,
flavorful way for the for the set
itself. And that's just really, really
cool. Um, big fan of these. Uh, there
are 10 of them, so to speak to possibly
a soupy format, but great stuff. Love
it.
And, uh, there you go. That's all them.
So, uncommon land hex haven dueling
arena adds a carous mana tap. This dark
creation of attack this turn becomes
prepared only the sorcery or four mana
creature has prepared. It's cute. Uh can
play with with the blue ameritus or the
white ameritus. Kind of cute. Uh but
yeah seems more cute than anything else.
It's very very slow and honestly most of
the prepared spells in this set are kind
of low impact. So
there's a lot of good color standard
right now. I don't think this one really
makes the uh makes the beach makes the
beach
meant off the bench if that works too.
Uh so thankfully the slow land cycle is
being finished here. Uh of course
deserted beach, haunted ridge, overgrown
farmland, rockfall veil and uh shipwreck
marsh. And even though the art on these
is pretty good, uh the original
Innistrad art I think is best land cycle
for art in my opinion in the entire
game. So get your Innistrad version cuz
they're really really cool. Um, but
yeah, these are great. These are like
the perfect standard lands. Um, they're
just great. I think they're they're
perfect. So, love them. We got Hall of
Echo. Co land. Tap five comes a copy of
target creature you control no turn with
no with no legend rule. Um,
it's cool. You know, it's kind of like a
creature land that can be any creature,
which is kind of amusing, but obviously
a big risk. uh where if you activate
this and they kill the thing, it get
response. Oh boy, that's rough. Um but
it's a cool land. Um only creatures, not
not other stuff. But yeah, I mean it's
cool. Probably not good enough, I don't
think. Um there might be some crazy
combo you can do with this, but looks
more commandery to me than standard.
Pretty good limited as we have time to
just copy your 55. It's pretty sweet. Um
but yeah, cool art though.
And then we have Roying Canopy. Um,
which is kind of weird.
I just don't saw. Never mind. I'm sorry.
I'm just I thought [laughter]
for a second I thought Valicate was
legendary. It's not obviously. So, uh,
Roy canopy enters tap. This is the green
Valicate. Whenever a forest enters, you
control at least five of their forest.
You have creature plus three and attacks
are green. Uh, clearly a lot worse than
valicet the molen pinnacle because it
doesn't just kill your opponent. That
being said, uh, Yavamaya exists, which
makes all ants forest. Kind of cute. And
the green fraian obliterator exists,
which you can get this in standard and
get a bunch of green sources. Kind of
cool also. Um, yeah, it's cool. The
problem, of course, it's on a far, so
like how many farest you going to play?
yada yada yada. Is there a monogreen
that wants to play this? Probably not.
But it's a cool card to have access to,
but definitely much worse than Valet is.
could be could be a fun draft card if
you're a monog green. But then we have
Theorist Sanctum.
This card I think is kind of fantastic.
Um
it's an island so you it is fetchable
which is cool. And as it enters you may
behold Jace if you don't comes in
tapped. So worst case land on turn one.
Uh, but if you are playing Jace
Planaineswalkers or if you have empower
stuff in your deck, this can be your
untapped land on turn four. And then
three mana to empower Jace 2 at instant
speed is pretty sweet. Uh, it's draw
two/3 of a card or surveil over and over
again. Uh, and again, you just just keep
doing it over and over again. It's
great. You know, it's endstep end step
pretty cheap. Uh, I card's awesome. The
card is really really cool for kind of
control decks, kind of planes walker
decks. I think the the opportunity cost
is pretty low. An island being an island
even turns your ves on which is sweet.
Uh so yeah, these cards sweet. Uh pretty
pretty big fan of empower juice 2 on the
land. That's why it's my sleeper card
and it's a phenomenal limited card too.
It's just ridiculously limited. Great
stuff.
So recapping carless we have K archer
defender as our best of sanctum is your
sleeper card ever your trap card and
murmuring volume your bombing common.
But wait, Billy May is here. There's
more. We're also going to do the bonus
sheet. Uh, sorry, the special guest
sheet. Uh, right now, too. The rope has
the bonus sheet. Um, I don't typically
do a section for these or even do them
often because, uh, like, you know. Wait,
hold on. Hold on. Hold on.
>> I'm in trouble.
>> Throw yourself in next time.
>> Your stupidity.
>> I'm in trouble.
>> What happened?
>> I mean, it's kind of your fault, too.
Uh, but
>> you you combine the
>> so I added Z to the beginning of each
best each award. So at the end of the
section, we go we we we recap them.
>> This is 100% your fault.
>> And Nicole used Z as her signifier to
put Ka and Verasa uh at the end of the
>> multiolor
>> multiard section. So I got to the recaps
>> uh and then they I missed them. So hold
on. Time out.
>> How did you realize Colonos and Lance?
>> What? Because no one said anything. I
mean, it's it's actually their fault.
>> I actually think I agree.
>> So, hold on. Hold on. So, we'll do these
real fast. So, sorry. Not sorry. It's
all K's fault. Um
>> I just
>> So,
>> it is always K's fault.
>> So, real fast. Uh K guildy guardian,
which is the carless card technically
kind of sort of. Uh, Wber and two
vigilant trample. When it enters, draw a
card for each color among other
artifacts you control. Five. Five. I
mean, this kind of just a commander card
anyway. Uh,
need to have colored artifacts in play.
Five colors. I mean, dinner spell is
good. Uh, yeah. It's not very good. And
limit extracted. Go back. Go back stuff.
And then Vasquez stone. So, soul of
stone just guy for a three. All our
creatures have vigilance. If you cast a
non-creature spell, make a one Carlos
sculptor token
would stack this to me. So a one- one
lotus pedals
again a commander card like three color
legends are not really good in standard.
I don't know what you want to do with
this card. Whatever. Didn't miss much.
Back to our bonus sheet stuff.
So anyway, um
it's who cares? It's it's the end of
Carlos. Not a lot of Carlos anyway. Um
so bonus sheet. Uh there are 10 sorry
it's not a bonus sheet. It's special
guests. So it's not a bonus sheet. These
are not impacts very often. These are
the guest cards. Only 10 of them. And
they are extremely infrequent impacts.
Uh meaning when you use lose to a steer
command, you're going to be
pissed.
>> Language.
[laughter] These are there's going to be
like one of these every like other draft
pod like one single copy. I think you
open one every like 50 pack or something
like that. Uh so a stir command is a
pretty big sweeper. Uh
the only real relevance these have is
for limited and for historic and
timeless on arena and historic command
is kind of whatever honestly. So, it's
the big six mana wrath unlimited. Sure.
Consider is a
is a common
>> cool uh early legal and everything. I
mean, it'll be good and limited in your
prowess deck. I don't know if it's, you
know, worth a guest card slot
of memory is unplayable in uh in
limited, but a card that's already on
arena, so not not relevant. Last Jupit
is a card I never seen before. I assume
it's a commander card, but blue blue for
a clone that lasts for three turns. It's
kind of cool, actually. Uh cool draft
card. And then might be cool in like
brawl and stuff uh on arena. It's kind
of cute. Supply Epiphany. Uh another
card you're going to smash your head in
your keyboard if you lose to it in
limited. Um
it's busted and limited, but already on
early arena. Mind twist is the big one.
[screaming]
Uh, Timeless Players, watch out. Dark
Patrol, Mind Twist. Uh, another card
where in limited you're going to be
pretty unhappy when your opponent casts
this against you, but again, you'll
never see it basically ever. Uh, we I
just guaranteed I'm getting mind twisted
in my first game of uh of my draft and
Sora, but sure. Necroinance, which is
honestly pretty fun and limited. It's
kind of a weird card, hard to play with,
but could be cool. Already on arena.
Splinter Twin, as we already mentioned,
there's a common Splinter Splinter,
Splinter Twin, a bull creature to combo
with in blue. So, this is actually a
very real card unlimited to watch out
for. If you first pick this, you could
easily play Blue Red, play a few of
those cards, and twin combo twin combo
people unlimited, which is fun. I don't
think this card's on arena either. I
don't think it matters for that much,
but it's uh it's kind of cool. Root Maze
is pretty irrelevant. Um, I think this
is already honor arena for timeless but
unplayable in uh in draft. And then Eye
of Ugan is another insane card for
timeless and historic uh probably
pre-banded historic but for timeless uh
on arena huge deal. Uh limited
unplayable. So there you go. There's a
bonus sheet. Uh and that's it. We're
done. Complete set review for Reality
Project is complete. I am freaking amped
to play with this set. Uh Tender Brews
Wednesday. Gonna be a lot of fun. Hope
to see you there. If you want to be
involved in the Discord, I always talk
to all y'all when I'm building my brews
and you all kind of help me out and
throw ideas at me, which is super cool.
And then of course, Bronze Mythic will
be on release day, Tuesday evening. A
lot of fun. Looking forward to y'all uh
in that one. And um otherwise, that's
it. I'm done, folks. I'm out of here.